Miranda Neerhof

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

miranda.neerhof@gmail.com
647-237-7061
mirandaneerhof.com
linkedin.com/in/mirandaneerhof
github.com/mirandajoy

PROFILE

My previous 7 years of experience working with software teams as a product manager and designer gave me the opportunity to see how excellent software is built. This experience, along with my natural aptitude to create, inspired me to become a software engineer.

As an analytical thinker that excels in solving complex problems both large and small, my diverse experience makes me an adaptable collaborator who can work effectively within a cross-functional team to deliver customer and business value.

SKILLS

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, DOM APIs, REST APIs, React, Node, Express, MySQL, Python, User Authentication, OAuth, GitHub, Heroku, Jest, Agile Development, Figma, UX Design

PROJECTS

Software Engineer | The Learning Club

JUL 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

 Developed a social platform for engaging and collaborative educational content using a React frontend and Express backend APIs.

Software Engineer | Tea Time at The Score

JUL 2024. BRAINSTATION HACKATHON

• Collaborated with a team of software engineers to produce a specialized news feed widget for The Score to engage users in the off-season.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

APR 2024 - JUL 2024, HALIFAX, NS

Mount Allison University | Bachelors in International Relations

SEPT 2009 - MAY 2012, SACKVILLE, NB

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Manager | CrowdRiff

SEPT 2021 - APR 2024, TORONTO, ON

- Led cross-functional efforts to discover product-market fit for a creator marketplace, achieving executive business alignment.
- Enabled efficient software delivery by crafting low-cost MVPs, leading to increased speed to market and faster early-stage validation in alignment with multiple teams.
- Utilized SQL/Postgres database skills to obtain crucial analytics which supported and validated product decision making.

Product Manager | CrowdRiff

DEC 2019 - SEPT 2021, TORONTO, ON

- Enhanced user experience by revamping core user workflows leading to increased utilization and engagement.
- Delivered software features by collaborating closely with product designers in order to increase MRR.
- Led agile processes with multiple engineering teams to minimize product delivery timelines.

Hybrid Product Manager and Designer | Plug in Useful

JUN 2017 - NOV 2019, TORONTO, ON

- Implemented UI by developing code in React with a Git workflow.
- Created product vision by developing the product roadmap, unlocking new revenue opportunities and increasing MRR by 100%.
- Owned a suite of 4 Shopify apps helping small businesses grow.